

Moscow, Russia

aleksandr-yakovlev

∂ aleksandr-yakovlev.github.io

⊠aleksandr.yakovlev@live.com

L +7 (963) 200-08-09

Skills

Management

Research & Strategy | Public Speaking | Flexibility | Agile | ITSM

ES6/ES7 | TS | React | Node.js | Jest | Webpack | Git

Data

Data Vault | Streaming | Cleansing | Visualization | Kafka | ClickHouse | Greenplum | ELK | Spark | Ni-fi

DevOps

Linux | Docker | OpenShift

Languages

English

Russian

Interests

Snowboard Swimming

Traveling Computer science

ALEKSANDR YAKOVLEV

CTO, Solution architect

IT enthusiast with 5+ years leadership experience in bringing product ideas to launch. Managing agile teams which are geographically distributed. I like engineering challenges passionate in technologies, performance and architecture. Open to relocation on a global level.

Experience

Sber · 7 yr

Teamlead · Regional control center

2021 - present · l yr

- revision of architecture
- transition to SaaS
 bringing ETL and BI
- prepare for a production

Solution Architect Products based on RegTech platform

2021 - present · l yı

- designing architecture
- platform consultation
- technical audit of a frontend app

Teamlead Intelligent transport system

2020 - 2021 · 1 yr

- creating POCsresearch of partner solutions
- · building a development teams

Teamlead · Analytical performance monitoring system

2015 - 2020 · 5 yr

- bringing product ideas to launch
- designing architecture
 implementing of support according to ITIL standards
- transition to cloud-native architecture
- transform to agile
- full HR-cycle

Alfabank - 3 yr

Middle developer

2012 - 2014 · 2 yr

- develop DWH
- develop FWTT
 develop frontends for local services
 building support processes based on ITIL

Middle engineer

2011 - 2012 · 1 yr

- building support processes on local offices
- interaction with contractorsIT budget management
- infrastructure managment and IT setup for new offices

Education

Northern (Arctic) Federal University named after M.V. Lomonosov

Information Systems and Technologies - 2012

Developer (university)

Computer Software 2009

Developer (college)